Okay, what up, yo? We're back with a
brand new video. Make sure you like and
subscribe if you appreciate the content.
Today, we are training a Laura on Flux
client and 9B. I um covered uh in my
latest video how to have consistent kind
of background across your images. Today,
I'm showing you how to have a consistent
character with your consistent
background. Uh we're going to do
everything on RunPod with AI Toolkit,
but this can be run uh locally if you
have, you know, the hardware necessary.
So, for Flux client, I would say you
need about uh 24 gigs of VRAM if you
want to be like safe. Uh
but in our case, we're going to be to be
using uh the Pro 6000.
Uh obviously, a 5090 will do the job,
I'm pretty sure. Uh locally, I have 5090
locally.
Um I'll use a Pro 6000 in this case, but
that's really kind of up to you between
a 5090.
Uh Pro 4500 could work as well, and uh
Pro 6000 are the best options for Flux
client.
Uh
so, yeah. I'll just choose my Pro 6000
here. Then, we go change template. And
we select the AI Toolkit ostrich
official. This is the official image um
made by the guy who made the thing.
And here for the storage, we're going to
be using uh volume disk. We don't need
the network volume for this. Um
after we're done training, it's
basically everything's going to be
deleted. So, we don't need to create a
full network volume for this. Uh it's
just not worth it. Then, we can deploy
on demand. Boom.
Uh it's going to be pretty fast. It's
just going to do everything that needs
to be done.
And uh open up the port for you. Uh so,
I'll be back when it's done.
Okay, so after a couple of really
seconds, you're going to have a new port
open here. HTTP service, you open that
up. Uh you enter the password, which is
password.
Go in.
Um so, first thing you have to do is add
your data set, obviously. Uh if you
don't have one, I've covered this
multiple times. Uh just go into school.
Uh there's a couple videos on how to uh
generate a data set. And in the sub
workflows, there are um a couple of
workflows that will let you do that
pretty easily.
Uh so, here, I'm just going to add a new
data set. I'm going to call it Lord
Farquaad
uh Klein.
And then add images. We're going to add
all our images. Uh in this case, I'm
going to use a really basic just face
data set. Uh I could use something uh
with body body images and everything,
but
I just don't want to right now. So, I'm
just going to use this, and this is
going to be the character we're
training. Um
it's the same face, just different hair
this time.
Uh so, yeah. Um
let me just
go over. Um
So, this, we don't need those two. We
can just delete one. Don't need both.
And those two look pretty much the same,
too.
So, let's say I'm happy with that. Then
we can go to uh the queue.
Uh new job.
Uh here we're going to be um
uh first of all, we need uh to add our
hugging face token.
Uh this can be got with uh hugging face.
You go there.
You go to access tokens.
And then you grab your uh token. Uh you
can just create a new one if you don't
already have one.
Uh just go here. Just type whatever you
need. Um select the first
four here.
Then you create your token. You copy it.
Then you go back to uh AI tool kit.
That's my old one.
Uh and you paste it in here and then you
save.
So, once it's saved, we can go to new
job
uh and go and ahead and select uh client
base 9B. We train on base, but we'll use
the normal version to generate uh
everything, obviously.
Uh here, you can just put whatever uh
keyword you need.
Uh
I'm not going to caption this today. Um
you can caption,
uh but personally, I really don't just
don't have uh
the will to do this at this point in
time. Uh
here,
cache the latent, we only train at 512
here.
And um the next thing we have to do,
we set this to three here.
The reason why we do that is because we
don't want every single goal uh human to
have the face of our character. So, we
just add that. And we use EMA.
Uh here, time step, I want to use
sigmoid and uh for the optimizer. So,
the learning rate I'm going to set to
one and for the optimizer, I'm going to
set it to uh prodigy.
So, here, optimizer, we set that to
prodigy.
Uh
and we good. Normally, you could use it
from here, but uh it seems to be
different if you use it from here if you
type it. So, I just like to type it in.
Um for the batch size, since we're using
a Pro 6000, we can go pretty well we can
go crazy here, but uh I'll just do two.
So, it's basically going to need uh
half the amount of steps to get the same
result.
That's the logic here. And since we save
every 150 frame, I'm going to go ahead
and sample every 150 frame so that the
sample kind of match the checkpoints.
Uh delete all the
um
sample prompts and then we can add our
sample prompts.
Uh here I'm just going to do uh
young uh woman taking a selfie in her
bedroom.
Uh she has
black hair and blue eyes, okay?
And blue eyes. Uh da and she is wearing
uh an
orange tank top.
Tank top.
Okay. Now that we have this, we can uh
basically just start the training. I'm
not going to lie. Um here we can set uh
the resolution. I want to have 1216 by
832.
And
uh we're basically ready to train at
this point.
So, let's do it. Uh we create a the job.
Boom.
And then we just start it.
So, technically uh the first thing it's
going to do I didn't change the name
here. You would have You would want to
change the name of the Laura, obviously.
Uh to whatever you need. That really
doesn't matter for the actual training,
but uh just for, you know,
classification purposes
uh having a proper name would help.
Uh so, here we're just going to download
the model. Um
the re- If you get errors at this point
before it even starts training, uh you
didn't put in your uh hugging face key
or something like that, right? So, just
make sure you have your hugging face key
in and make sure you went on uh the
actual model page for Flux client and
uh you got accepted. Uh you'll need to
ask for access here.
Uh, once you have access, you'll be able
to train on, um, the model.
So, yeah. Uh, here
just going to wait up for it to start
up, and then, um,
I'll come back at the end and basically
show you all the samples and everything,
and that's going to be the video.
I can do anything over 15 minutes on
this new channel, so that's going to be
it for you.
Uh, but, I mean, the rest of the content
is going to be on the sub, um, for the
school subscribers. So, uh, shoutout to
y'all, and, uh, yeah, I'll see you when
uh, the samples are done. Let's get it.
Okay, so we are back. We're
pretty much done with the training. Um,
so I'll go over the samples, and, uh,
I'll show then we're going to go into
comfyui and basically test those out.
Uh, the samples might be a little bad,
but that doesn't mean that the actual
Laura will be bad, so, uh, let's go over
it. This is, uh, zero steps, so that's
the first before training everything.
That's kind of the baseline.
Uh, this is 150 steps. Uh, remember,
since we have a batch size of two, it's
basically 300 steps here.
Uh, this is, uh,
basically 600 steps.
And after 600 steps, it kind of starts
to degrade in the samples. Um, I think
it's pretty obvious that this does not
look like our character at all, and then
at 750, we get some weird [__] like
some weird weird [__] you feel me?
So,
um,
we're going to test those out, uh, in
comfyui and see if it actually matches,
but I think, uh, the 600 of 450
are going to be
uh, uh, the ones I end up using even
though the samples look pretty bad. So,
let's get into Comfy and test those out.
Okay, so we are back in uh, ComfyUI. Uh,
here this is what I generated with
uh, the first Laura. So, the 150.
Now, we're going to go to 300
uh, which is the next checkpoint. So,
it's going to be this one. Just run
that.
Should be pretty fast here. Okay, so now
the eye color is matching what we expect
and the hair color is also um,
closer to what we had in the data set.
Now, if we go 450,
which is the next checkpoint, these are
all the same seeds. So, this is kind of
a consistent um,
you know, parameter. And here I would
say it looks a little bit more uh, like
our character again.
And then if we go to the next, which is
600,
it's going to be this one.
Run that. I think it looks even more
like our data set if we remember
um,
the data set looks like
like this.
So, I would say this looks like this
pretty much. They're pretty much the
same. I'm not going to lie.
So, yeah. Um,
let's go back here. And then if we want
to go even further and see if it kind of
starts to collapse, uh, the next one is
750.
And this is where I can say that it's
broken, overtrained. Why? Because we
lost all the composition.
Uh, the framing is bad, the logic is
bad, everything is just bad, right?
Well, if we go back to Now, if we go
back to 600 for example, just to see,
uh we're going to log the seed
and then run it again.
And we get something that looks a way
more um
you know, composed and real.
So, 600
450 would be where I kind of
uh
you know, say that it's trained up.
Uh so, this 600 this is 450 now.
Yeah. So, 450 600 I'm pretty happy with
either of those uh and then those can be
used with my prior workflow to actually
put them uh the character directly in
whatever scene you wanted the character
to be
and uh be consistent about it. So, yeah,
that's pretty much it. Uh you already
know, man. Join the school. Join the
Discord and uh I'll be seeing you in the
next one. Peace.